HATIM ALATTAS

Software Engineer

- +966 56 613 1333 @ alattas96@outlook.com
- % https://www.linkedin.com/in/hatimalattas https://github.com/hatimalattas ♥ Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

SUMMARY

I am a self-motivated software engineer who enjoys solving problems and building web applications!
I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital experiences. My repertoire includes programming languages and tools such as ReactJS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Bootstrap and more.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Participant)

Misk Academy - General Assembly

11/2019 - 02/2020

✓ Jeddah

- Built the famous game Connect 4, a front-end web application that users can see and interact with, leveraging JavaScript, jQuery HTML, and CSS
- Built a full stack application using Ruby on Rails that authenticate users and allow them to review stadiums and stores data in MySQL database
- As member of a team, I developed the front-end using React for a full-stack application called Menu App, which is a platform to present restaurants menus for viewers to check the desired restaurant menu (Built with React and Ruby on Rails)
- As a team member, I worked in the front-end and the back-end using React and Express to build GetFit App, which is a full-stack application to present information related to health, diets, workouts, products, where the user can set goals and calculate calories intake (Built with React, Express, Ruby on Rails)

Software Developer (Research Intern)

Ryerson University

1 06/2018 - 09/2018

Project Title: Further development of graphical structural analysis software using C++ language.

- Successfully modeled axially-loaded circular columns subjected to lateral impact loads due to accidental ship collisions
- Verified the developed computer models using experimental results available in the literature

AWARDS



Excellent Grade with Second Class Honors



Dean's Honor List



Superior Certificate



4th place in the Mathematics Excellence Competition

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native •••• English

Fluent ••••

♀ Toronto

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End

JavaScript jQuery Bootstrap 4

ReactJS HTML5 CSS3

Back End

PostgreSQL MongoDB MySQL

ExpressJS Flask Ruby on Rails

Tools

Git npm Rest APIs pip conda

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Program

Misk Academy - General Assembly

2019 - 2020

- Requirements included the attendance of 480 hours of face-to-face instruction, completion of course projects, as well as the successful completion of the capstone presentation
- Key Course Topics: Application Programming, Problem Solving Strategies, Git, Github, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, React, RESTful API, Full Stack Development and Deployment, Authentication and Authorization, Algorithms, Data structure, Design Patterns and Presentation Skills

BS in Electrical & Computer Engineering

University of Jeddah

2014 - 2019

• Senior Design Project:

Designed a control system that can decide the number of air conditioners that should be operating based on the number of people inside a building using Arduino, photoresistor, and RF Transceiver

GPA 4.5 / 5.0

 Relevant courses completed: Computer Programming, Computer Networks, Digital Logic Design, Microprocessors & Microcontrollers